<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/feed/docs.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-18T15:29:30-05:00</updated><id>https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/feed/docs.xml</id><title type="html">Minimal Mistakes | Docs</title><subtitle>A flexible Jekyll theme for your blog or site with a minimalist aesthetic.</subtitle><author><name>Michael Rose</name></author><entry><title type="html">Blockchain Basics</title><link href="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/blockchain-basics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blockchain Basics" /><published>2019-02-18T15:29:30-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T22:21:33-05:00</updated><id>https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/06-blockchain-basics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/blockchain-basics/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;blockchain-basics&quot;&gt;Blockchain Basics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, we have discussed the impressive implications of blockchain technology. We will now simply and concisely explain how the technology works to make it transparent and immutable across all users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain is a digital ledger that operates via a network of computers. Data added to the blockchain is visible to everyone participating. When a transaction is carried out on the blockchain, it is added to a cryptographically encoded “block” with all the other transactions that occurred in the last ten minutes (for the Bitcoin network) and shared with the entire network of computers. Members of the network with participating computers, otherwise known as &lt;strong&gt;miners&lt;/strong&gt;, compete to solve these cryptographic puzzles to validate the transaction. The first miner to decode the puzzle receives a small reward from the network for their work. The puzzle is difficult to solve, so in order to solve the puzzle fast enough to receive the reward, a miner will use powerful computers. When Bitcoin was first launched, it was possible to use a laptop purchased in a store for mining. That is no longer the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ‘validation’ is in the form of reviewing cryptographic inputs, outputs and a timestamp, which then allows validated blocks to be linked to older validated blocks. This forms a chain of blocks that show every transaction made on the blockchain. This chain is updated and is made accessible to every member on the platform. This decentralized quality allows for transparency and immutability - that anyone on the platform has the ability to view any data added to the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hashing-and-public-key-cryptography&quot;&gt;Hashing and Public Key Cryptography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain uses hash functions in order to create an immutable record of what is written to it, as well as to create “digital signatures”. A hash function is a digital mechanism that is used to compress data into a specific format. The hashing algorithm used by the Bitcoin blockchain is SHA-256. In this hash, the hashed data is always 256 bits long. The Ethereum blockchain uses a hashing algorithm called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/Ethash&quot;&gt;Ethash&lt;/a&gt;. A hash created using Ethash will look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-text highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;0xb846300e188829d1b819389b31cef3b9cfaf335082ee66f830a875f1c1beb396
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above hash is from block 5000171 mined at Jan-30-2018 02:20:28 PM +UTC on the Ethereum blockchain. More data on this block can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://etherscan.io/block/5000171&quot;&gt;Etherscan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This hashed data is used on the blockchain to indicate value and the links between each specific blocks. In addition to hashing, the blockchain relies on public key cryptography to encode information securely - the digital signatures we referred to in the above paragraph. Specifically, participants on the blockchain have a private code - called private keys - that allow them to access their information which is encoded with a public code - called a public key. The public and private key are related, but a malicious actor cannot derive the private key from the visible public key. Private keys are not meant to be shared since a private key is used to unlock its associated public key. These keys sign transactions on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yunyun Chen of ConsenSys created an excellent visual explaining hashing in &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.consensys.net/guide-hashing-33dc0467c126&quot;&gt;Guide: Hashing&lt;/a&gt; and how it is a part of public key cryptography in &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.consensys.net/guide-an-introduction-to-encryption-9afd17f5da6d&quot;&gt;Guide: An Introduction to Encryption&lt;/a&gt;. Both graphics are reproduced below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../.gitbook/assets/guide-hashing.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../.gitbook/assets/guide-an-introduction-to-encrpytion.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hashing and public key cryptography work hand in hand to maintain consensus in the system. Through consensus, the entire system has common knowledge of the happenings on the platform and any action is recorded and made available for the platform to view. This solves the issue of a trustless system with intermediaries because now, participants on the blockchain have constant verification on the platform. The process of miners verifying actions on the blockchain is known as &lt;strong&gt;proof of work&lt;/strong&gt;. Mining ensures that the constant state of the ledger has transactions that are all true. This prevents attacks and false information from perpetuating within the system, ensuring lasting validity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael Rose</name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">A Brief History of Blockchain</title><link href="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/history-of-blockchain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Brief History of Blockchain" /><published>2019-02-18T15:29:30-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T22:21:33-05:00</updated><id>https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/05-history-of-blockchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/history-of-blockchain/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-brief-history-of-blockchain&quot;&gt;A Brief History of Blockchain&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the concept of a blockchain was first fully actualized in Satoshi Nakamoto’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;, the underlying concepts and technologies draws from years of research across cryptography, computing, and economics. In this section we will uncover some of this history:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start with the idea of centralization. Centralization, or control by a single authority or entity, is a common and pervasive form of governance. We trust (or lack trust of) central authorities, like banks, governments, and other institutions to maintain order and structure within the space they operate. This trust is not universally earned by every central authority, as there are many examples where the trust given to the authority is broken. Sony employees have had their social security numbers stolen from employee databases, Target customers have had their credit card information stolen, banks have compromised user accounts to thieves, and governments have taken away the rights of their citizens. Centralized technology and data allows for the monopolization of power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems in centralization came to a head in the global financial crisis that occurred in 2008. On October 31, 2008, in the midst of the financial crisis, Satoshi Nakamoto (an alias for a still unidentified individual or group of individuals) published the &lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin Whitepaper&lt;/strong&gt;, titled &lt;em&gt;Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System&lt;/em&gt;. This paper described a peer-to-peer electronic cash system, Bitcoin, that combines cryptography, computer science, and game theory in its design and implementation. Satoshi’s creation enabled a participant to digitally transact directly with another participant without relying on an intermediary, such as a bank, to process the payments. When we say peer-to-peer, we are essentially describing a transaction from one entity directly to another entity. There is no intermediary the transaction has to pass through. For example, if you schedule a payment via a banking app on your phone to a friend of yours, the actual flow of money goes from an account controlled by your bank to an account controlled by your friend’s bank. If your friend does not have a bank account, you could send the money from your bank to a third party, like a money transfer company, where your friend could pick up the money. Even if you withdrew the money from the bank and mailed it to your friend, you would need to have an address to send it to and rely on the speed of your postal service to get the money there safely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin attracted attention for its ability to allow for peer-to-peer transactions without a centralized intermediary. Technologists were drawn to the &lt;strong&gt;blockchain&lt;/strong&gt;, the underlying technology on which Bitcoin operates. To remind you, a blockchain is a decentralized ledger that records transactions or activity between two participants permanently with verification.This verification comes in the form of reviewing cryptographic functions and timestamps. Transactions can be verified on multiple computers, which are referred to as nodes. This makes the blockchain decentralized and transparent. Blockchain technology can be uncoupled from the Bitcoin protocol and can be used for many other kinds of cryptocurrencies. It can also be applied to many industry wide use cases, specifically provenance tracking and management, creative rights management, patient records, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the surge of attention to the Bitcoin codebase and white paper, Vitalik Buterin, a contributor to the community, saw some limitations in the design of Bitcoin and began designing an open source protocol starting in late 2013, now known as &lt;strong&gt;Ethereum.&lt;/strong&gt; Ethereum also operates on a blockchain, but it allows for other digital assets to be recorded on the ledger, unlike the Bitcoin blockchain. Released in 2015, the Ethereum protocol allows for programmable instructions, or &lt;strong&gt;smart contracts&lt;/strong&gt;, to be built around a set of transactions, which automates many processes. This ability helps make the Ethereum blockchain more malleable than other blockchains. The Ethereum blockchain operates with Ether (ETH), the digital token that powers functions and is necessary to run decentralized applications.  &lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his article &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.consensys.net/it-was-the-best-of-times-it-was-the-worst-of-times-3fc8c0865c6c&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here Comes the Epoch of Blockchain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Andrew Keys, Head of Business Development at ConsenSys, lays out the areas of our world that are centralized, why it causes issues, and how blockchain can be a catalyst for change. He emphasizes that the Ethereum blockchain gives users the ability to program interactions with other users - if you do this, I will give you this - opening up new possibilities for people from all over the world to interact with each other. The promise of blockchain that is beginning to be realized is that a blockchain can give anyone the opportunity to interact with anyone else, and not have to trust a central authority in the process. This is incredibly powerful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael Rose</name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Principles of Decentralization</title><link href="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/principles-of-decentralization/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Principles of Decentralization" /><published>2019-02-18T15:29:30-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T22:21:33-05:00</updated><id>https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/04-principles-of-decentralization</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/principles-of-decentralization/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;principles-of-decentralization&quot;&gt;Principles of Decentralization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used the word decentralization in “What’s the Big Deal”, but have not spent too much time defining this concept which is key to blockchain. So what does decentralization mean? In this section we will seek to understand various definitions of decentralization, and how members of the blockchain community have applied that definition to development of the technology. A good way to think about decentralization is to associate the word with a transfer of authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three main forms of decentralization, or how authority is transferred. Vitalik Buterin, the founder of Ethereum, detailed the following three forms of decentralization in a post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@VitalikButerin/the-meaning-of-decentralization-a0c92b76a274&quot;&gt;medium account&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Architectural (de)centralization&lt;/strong&gt; — how many &lt;strong&gt;physical computers&lt;/strong&gt; is a system made up of? How many of those computers can it tolerate breaking down at any single time?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political (de)centralization&lt;/strong&gt;  — how many &lt;strong&gt;individuals or organizations&lt;/strong&gt; ultimately control the computers that the system is made up of?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logical (de)centralization&lt;/strong&gt; — does the &lt;strong&gt;interface and data structures&lt;/strong&gt; that the system presents and maintains look more like a single monolithic object, or an amorphous swarm? One simple heuristic is: if you cut the system in half, including both providers and users, will both halves continue to fully operate as independent units?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get specific with an example. The computer or tablet on which you are reading this book was very likely made by a company with a CEO and a board of executives. This company is very likely structured to have business units that take care of various components of building, marketing, and selling the device you are using. The CEO and the board of executives provide direction to the different business units so they can work together to build computers. If the company were to split up, the CEO and board of executives would have to decide (or be incentivized) to split the company up. The individual parts of the company could not decide to do that on their own. If the part of the company that assembles the keyboards decided they no longer wanted to be part of the larger company, they really do not have the choice to break off into another company. According to Vitalik, this means the company is &lt;strong&gt;logically centralized.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example that Vitalik uses is language. For most languages, there is no centralized infrastructure enforcing people to speak in a certain way. While there are best practices and grammar rules that are most typically followed, no centralized authority polices a person’s everyday use of language. Organizations that publish dictionaries do not have direct control over the language. People who speak the language are the ones with control over it. This is how we see language evolve over time, depending on the place and time in which it is spoken and written. An example is how Latin over time evolved into the modern day romance languages of Spanish, French, Italian, Portuguese, Romanian, and Catalan. No central authority decided that Latin should evolve into these languages. In this case, language is something that is &lt;strong&gt;logically decentralized.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of blockchains, they are &lt;strong&gt;politically decentralized&lt;/strong&gt; because no one person has singular control over them. They are also a&lt;strong&gt;rchitecturally decentralized&lt;/strong&gt; because there is no infrastructural central point of failure, as each node keeps a copy of the blockchain. But, blockchains are &lt;strong&gt;logically centralized&lt;/strong&gt; because the system behaves like one computer despite being spread apart on all the participating nodes in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-decentralization-useful&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is Decentralization Useful?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the characteristics of a blockchain, decentralization (politically and architecturally) allows blockchains to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Less likely to fail because they rely on many separate components.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harder to attack because the networks are spread across many computers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harder for users with malicious intent to take advantage of users who are using the platform for its intended purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If one node stops working, or even 100 nodes, the blockchain survives assuming there is at least one node up and running. This makes the blockchain very resistant to attacks. The blockchain does not stop working even if the power is lost in an entire country. This makes the blockchain very resilient, which cannot be said of many of the existing systems on which we associate with the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-do-we-go-from-here&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where do we go from here?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phrase Web 3 is used to indicate that we are going past Web 1.0 (the original protocols of the Internet) and Web 2.0 (the responsive web, which is the Internet as we know it in 2018). But what does this actually mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, companies like Facebook, Amazon, and Google dominate the Internet. They offer many free or cheap services because they are able to collect valuable data on their users, and find ways to monetize that data. As a user of the modern internet, one is never too sure where their demographic and personal data is being used. Through the implementation of decentralization, also called Web 3, data does not have to be stored in centralized systems. Data can be verified independently and content creators are valued by the quality of their work. Micropayments become a feasible method of being rewarded for value created. Users control how their data is used and accessed over the Internet, and can be paid for the use of their data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all possible through the usage of blockchain protocols which can be operationalized by Ethereum, Bitcoin, etc. Jesse Grushack, the founder of Ujo lays out the problem of users becoming the product for digital advertisers in Web 2.0 and how the Ethereum blockchain can flip this model on its head, in this article on ConsenSys media, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ConsenSys/welcome-to-3-0-f4552fb02302&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to 3.0&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you finish reading this section, we want you to come away with the following: Decentralization disintermediates central control of systems. Instead of a single company being responsible for writing information to the blockchain, the responsibility falls to anyone who wants to participate in the system. This is a significant shift in thinking, but an important one to understanding why blockchains are so important - they are both philosophically and technically engineered to be different from the centralized systems we are familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael Rose</name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">What’s the big deal?</title><link href="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/whats-the-big-deal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What's the big deal?" /><published>2019-02-18T15:29:30-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T22:21:33-05:00</updated><id>https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/03-whats-the-big-deal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/whats-the-big-deal/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;whats-the-big-deal&quot;&gt;What’s the Big Deal?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You keep hearing about Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies via the news, social media, and even late night talk shows. Considerable amount of newspaper and magazine space has been dedicated to articles about the rise of cryptocurrencies. There have been profiles of individuals who are movers and shakers in the space - Bitcoin millionaires, crypto-nomads, and people who only use cryptocurrency. Strong opinions on cryptocurrencies are being expressed and there are claims that blockchain will change the world. What is going on here? Did you miss something along the way? How is a person supposed to keep up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be fair to say that Bitcoin’s past has not been the most accessible to the general public. An anonymous individual or group with the name Satoshi Nakamoto self-published a paper in October 2008 to a mailing list describing a peer to peer electronic cash system (referred to as the Bitcoin Whitepaper). As word spread, explanations of Bitcoin’s importance have competed with images of upward trending price charts that caused people to be overwhelmingly skeptical or excited about this digital currency. The &lt;strong&gt;blockchain&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the name for the technologies that together underpin the cryptocurrency Bitcoin, has begun to get more attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-blockchain&quot;&gt;What is a blockchain?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A blockchain is a public distributed ledger, in which all who choose to participate in it have autonomy to access it. Simply put, a blockchain is like a spreadsheet anyone can access. Every participant has a copy of the spreadsheet and is responsible for keeping it up to date. This is a purposeful oversimplification, as this guide will show you in later chapters (using a blockchain to store data as if it were a spreadsheet or even a database does not always make sense, and vice versa). However, we are going to temporarily use this analogy to tie blockchain back to a technology you may already know and use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like we said, anyone choosing to participate in the blockchain has the autonomy to access it. Some individuals use that autonomy to download the blockchain to their own computer and play a role in maintaining the blockchain. When the blockchain is downloaded and maintained on a computer, it is referred to as a “&lt;strong&gt;node&lt;/strong&gt;”. Those running a “node” have a copy of the blockchain. This copy is actively updated along with every copy on every other node. The blockchain is maintained collaboratively and does not have a single central entity maintaining the ledger. Edits can only be made to the blockchain with general consensus among the individuals running the nodes. When consensus is reached, new data is added to the blockchain. Therefore, all participants are recording the agreed upon changes to the blockchain. There were an estimated 11,924 Bitcoin nodes operating on February 1st, 2018 according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitnodes.earn.com/&quot;&gt;Bitnodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data on the blockchain is made secure through the creation of hashes, hexadecimal numbers that are created using all the data from the blockchain each time a new block is created. Hexadecimal what? For now, let’s think of hexadecimal is a base 16 number system - we are much more familiar with the base 10 number system and some may be familiar with base 2 (also known as binary). Hexidecimal numbers look like this: BF35 (48,949 in base 10). Putting data into hexidecimal hashes allows for a high density of information to be encrypted in a consistent format, typically in a hash of a fixed length. This allows for large amounts of data making up the blockchain to be written to a fixed length hash. As the blockchain grows bigger, the number of characters in the hash will always be the same length (the characters themselves change). This is part of a set of rules that makes the blockchain secure - any change to the blockchain will cause a change in the resulting hash, and alert us that the state of the blockchain has changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use cases for the blockchain are now rampant: information about an individual’s identity can be stored on the blockchain, banks can record transactions using blockchains, and copyright licenses can be issued via this transparent framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain is engineered to be open to anyone who has a computer terminal and decentralized so there is no single decision-making authority. No central authority holds power to make decisions and enforce rules. An issue with a system that is open and decentralized is that careful consideration must be given to incentivize individuals to not only participate, but behave in a manner that is not detrimental to other users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;influence-on-economic-systems&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influence on Economic Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital currency can be thought of as a tool that enables people in different regions and countries to trade with each other without worrying about an exchange rate or transfer fee from one banking system to another. The excitement we have seen around cryptocurrencies comes from their potential to enable easier exchange of value from an entity to any other entity. More individuals would have the opportunity to buy or sell anything from theoretically anyone from nearly anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-ethereum&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Ethereum?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum is an open source, programmable blockchain platform that allows for the development of decentralized applications (or DApps - sometimes stylized as dApps). It was created and conceptualized by Vitalik Buterin. Ethereum runs smart contracts. &lt;strong&gt;Smart contracts&lt;/strong&gt; are pieces of code that allow the Ethereum blockchain to immediately transport or move data without an intermediary. No central authority is required to cause the code in a smart contract to run - the code runs based on the rules contained within it. The “rules” of a smart contract can be thought of as automatically initiated (sanctioned) after the contract is activated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum has received significant support from an ecosystem that has formed around it, with existing and new institutions creating DApps, tools, conferences, forums, meetups, and companies to support and accelerate the adoption of this new technology. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ethereum.org/foundation&quot;&gt;Ethereum Foundation&lt;/a&gt; developed Ethereum, and retains the role of an open source project aimed at building out improvements to the software, as well as developing protocols. Some enterprises have further supported the adoption of Ethereum by creating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://entethalliance.org/&quot;&gt;Enterprise Ethereum Alliance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralized products and solutions built on Ethereum have already hit market. Companies are finding solutions for preventing identity theft, improving crowdfunding, paying musicians more fairly for their work, tracking food from farms to grocery stores, and many other use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-to-come&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s to come?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Ethereum use cases are plenty, this technology promises something larger than just a few thousand applications. Creators of these blockchain-based applications can tap into new ways to fund the development of the applications. They can also find new ways for their users to interact with the applications themselves. Tokenization allows for the distribution of &lt;strong&gt;tokens -&lt;/strong&gt; representations of value or the permission to do some actions within an application. For example, a token could represent an opportunity to play a video game or download a song. These tokens are specific to the application. Tokenizing an application is done on top of the Ethereum blockchain, giving creators of DApps new ways to do business on an open source system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of tokens like keys that allow a user to participate in the system, rather than a stock ownership certificate. The founders of the network keep a percentage of the tokens for themselves and if the network gains popularity, demand for the tokens rise while supply remains constant, making the price of the tokens increase. Founders can now monetize the networks they build by tokenizing their system and increasing the value of the system to the users. Ether (ETH) is the token for Ethereum. Any DApp built on top of Ethereum can also use Ether, or create a new token specific to their application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example is tokenizing social networks and current day media platforms. Each platform’s value is designated by its users. As a user, for the first time, it would be possible to purchase a portion of a system and power its entire protocol. While a lot of this is hypothetical, furthering the experimentation and education around blockchain technology gets us a step closer to this kind of future. Decentralized blockchain protocols have the ability to displace centralized internet systems and providers to the point that each user of the internet will ultimately be sovereign.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael Rose</name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">How to use this guide</title><link href="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/how-to-use-this-guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to use this guide" /><published>2019-02-18T15:29:30-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T22:21:33-05:00</updated><id>https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/02-how-to-use-this-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/how-to-use-this-guide/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-ask-questions-comment-and-contribute&quot;&gt;How to Ask Questions, Comment, and Contribute&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, thank you for wanting to engage with us! One of the things that makes the Ethereum community so wonderful is their willingness to collaborate to make wonderful tools for learning. Interacting with you will help us improve our products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-found-a-link-that-does-not-work-or-a-citation-that-leads-to-outdated-information&quot;&gt;I found a link that does not work, or a citation that leads to outdated information.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, times slows for no one. Products break, code does not compile, and our documentation becomes progressively outdated. If you find a citation or link that fits this description, please do the two following things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, report the issue on the publishing platform. Second, if you have the time (and want to do a good deed for others who purchased the book) and find where that citation has moved to, you are more than welcome to let us know via this &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfOH5EOwqUvpfu86MsEfYAK_76A0KPOb8D71LSObpLVTHJRZg/viewform?usp=sf_link&quot;&gt;form&lt;/a&gt;, and we will push out an updated version of the book to all purchasers periodically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-want-to-you-to-add-a-pagewant-you-to-add-more-detail&quot;&gt;I want to you to add a page/want you to add more detail.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let us know what information you want more detail on. As we hear from readers, we can push updates to this book to include more detail or clarity. We hope you will find this update feature useful, and allow you to continue to engage with the book over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-have-a-question-comment-or-a-concern&quot;&gt;I have a question, comment, or a concern&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please fill out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfOH5EOwqUvpfu86MsEfYAK_76A0KPOb8D71LSObpLVTHJRZg/viewform?usp=sf_link&quot;&gt;form&lt;/a&gt;, which will alert the team of your inquiry and we will respond promptly as we work to address your inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-are-happy-to-accept-all-worthwhile-submissions-cheers&quot;&gt;We are happy to accept all worthwhile submissions! Cheers!&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Michael Rose</name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Before We Begin</title><link href="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/before-we-begin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Before We Begin" /><published>2019-02-18T15:29:30-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T22:21:33-05:00</updated><id>https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/01-before-we-begin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/before-we-begin/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;before-we-begin&quot;&gt;Before We Begin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide will help you develop a mental model of blockchain technology in order to help you understand its impact on society and business. By the end of this book you should have basic knowledge of the underpinnings of blockchain technology, specifically the Ethereum blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide does not have to be read start to finish. Rather, it is an index of subjects which you can reference to get an understanding of certain concepts. The blockchain industry is a collaborative one, and as such, this guide will cite materials both internal and external to ConsenSys. We believe these materials are key in pushing the discussion further than the limitations of this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-this-guide-for-me&quot;&gt;Is this guide for me?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide is designed for anyone who is looking to wrap their head around blockchain technology, how it works, and how it could affect the world around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a more technical background, such as a developer with experience building software, please look out for our coding based offerings, which cover setting up the developer tools and building on top of the Ethereum blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-this-guide-is-not&quot;&gt;What this guide is not&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide is not how to set up a wallet and start buying and trading cryptocurrencies. It does not give you advice on which cryptocurrencies to buy. Other resources are a better fit for that, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://silentcicero.gitbooks.io/pro-tips-for-ethereum-wallet-management/&quot;&gt;Pro-Tips for Ethereum Wallet Management by Nick Dodson&lt;/a&gt;, for an example of a wallet set up resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overlapping-resources&quot;&gt;Overlapping resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because this guide is an introduction to key concepts, there will be times when sections might overlap in content or scope. This guide was written to explain blockchain simply and concisely, so many ideas will be repeated. There are links to additional information to offer different mediums of communication (video, for example) to fit diverse learning styles. It is suggested that a complete beginner read all of the sections of this guide. Going over the topics in multiple sections can be a good review of material and are presented using different examples. However, how you use this guide is up to you, and if you ever encounter a topic you feel you are already familiar with, feel free to skip it and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updates&quot;&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of this ever growing and changing space, purchasers of this book will get updates via the publishing platform when they are available. This will allow you to keep up to date about what is going on. We will also include relevant information about in-person or virtual discussions of topics within the book and how those will be facilitated.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael Rose</name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/introduction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2019-02-18T15:29:30-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-25T22:21:33-05:00</updated><id>https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/00-introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/blockchain-basics/introduction/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide will help you develop a mental model of blockchain technology in order to help you understand its impact on society and business. By the end of this book you should have basic knowledge of the underpinnings of blockchain technology, specifically the Ethereum blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide does not have to be read start to finish. Rather, it is an index of subjects which you can reference to get an understanding of certain concepts. The blockchain industry is a collaborative one, and as such, this guide will cite materials both internal and external to ConsenSys. We believe these materials are key in pushing the discussion further than the limitations of this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-this-guide-for-me&quot;&gt;Is this guide for me?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide is designed for anyone who is looking to wrap their head around blockchain technology, how it works, and how it could affect the world around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a more technical background, such as a developer with experience building software, please look out for our coding based offerings, which cover setting up the developer tools and building on top of the Ethereum blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-this-guide-is-not&quot;&gt;What this guide is not&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide is not how to set up a wallet and start buying and trading cryptocurrencies. It does not give you advice on which cryptocurrencies to buy. Other resources are a better fit for that, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://silentcicero.gitbooks.io/pro-tips-for-ethereum-wallet-management/&quot;&gt;Pro-Tips for Ethereum Wallet Management by Nick Dodson&lt;/a&gt;, for an example of a wallet set up resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overlapping-resources&quot;&gt;Overlapping resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because this guide is an introduction to key concepts, there will be times when sections might overlap in content or scope. This guide was written to explain blockchain simply and concisely, so many ideas will be repeated. There are links to additional information to offer different mediums of communication (video, for example) to fit diverse learning styles. It is suggested that a complete beginner read all of the sections of this guide. Going over the topics in multiple sections can be a good review of material and are presented using different examples. However, how you use this guide is up to you, and if you ever encounter a topic you feel you are already familiar with, feel free to skip it and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;updates&quot;&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of this ever growing and changing space, purchasers of this book will get updates via the publishing platform when they are available. This will allow you to keep up to date about what is going on. We will also include relevant information about in-person or virtual discussions of topics within the book and how those will be facilitated.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael Rose</name></author></entry></feed>